Norman Lo

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/norman-data-economist Phone: (415) 706-8788

GitHub: https://github.com/NormanLo4319

Address: San Francisco, CA 94107 Website: https://normanlo4319.github.io/Norman Lo Web E-mail: lokmannorman@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Data scientist with several years of experience in academic research and data analysis. Experienced in data management and statistical packages, such as Javascript, Python, R, Stata, MatLab, E-View, VBA, and SQL. Motivated to bring background in academic research and ability to build econometrics models with visualization to enhance decision-making and achieve company goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python, R, Stata, E-View, MatLab, SQL, noSQL, VBA

Data Manipulation & Visualization: pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Plotly, D3, ggplot2, scikits, sicpy

Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB, SQLAlchemy

Other: Git, Flask, command line, machine learning, big data analysis

PROJECTS

Research Paper Web Scraping Project (Lead of the Research Team at USF)

- Use BeautifulSoup and Splinter scraping the early-childhood research papers from different web sites.
- Store data into database and analyze data with Numpy and Scipy.

Shopping Recommendation App (Lead of the Independent Web Development Team)

- Built a full function web/mobile application to enhance in-store shopping experience.
- Used machine learning (logistic regression and Xception model) to make recommendation to in-store customers.

World Happiness Project (Individual Contributor)

- Built a back-end API with SQLAlchemy and Flask for data request.
- Created front-end data product to request data from the API and provided visualizations for clients.
- Demonstrated the correlation between happiness and income inequality across 156 countries.

Public Health Scores & Yelp Customer-Based Rating (Independent Research Project)

- Analyzed the restaurants' public health score and Yelp customer-based rating in San Francisco.
- Pulled and stored data from Yelp API and SFDPH on over 2000 restaurants into SQL database.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist, Code with Corgis, San Francisco

(2019 – present)

- Support product and leadership teams with insights gained from analyzing company data.
- Utilizing statistics learning to drive optimization and improvement of product development and business strategies.
- Develop custom data models and algorithms to apply to data set.
- Using A/B testing framework and test model quality.
- Develop processes and tools to monitor and analyze model performance and data accuracy.

Adjunct Faculty, DVC, SFSU, USF, CCSF, Metro. State University (2015 – present) Student Equity Economics Advisor, City College of San Francisco (2017 - present) Native English ESL Teacher, South Korea (2010 - 2013)Merchandising Manager, First Global International Ltd, Hong Kong (2007 - 2010)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: U.C. Berkeley Extension, San Francisco

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programing skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL

Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

M.A. in Economics: San Francisco State University, San Francisco B.A. in Economics: San Francisco State University, San Francisco